片名: 红色警戒
What's this war in the heart of nature?
世上为何有这么多战争?
Why does nature vie with itself?
万物为何自相残杀?
The land contend with the sea?
陆地和海洋为何互相对抗?
Is there an avenging power in nature?
大自然是否充满仇恨?
Not one power, but two?
善恶是否同时存在?
I remember my mother when she was dying.
我记得我母亲临终前
Looked all shrunk up and grey.
脸色苍白 形如槁木
I asked her if she was afraid.
我问她害不害怕?
She just shook her head.
她只是摇摇头
I was afraid to touch the death seen in her.
我不敢面对她的死亡
I couldn't find nothing beautiful or up lifting about her going back to God.
也不觉得她蒙主荣召是一件好事
I heard people talk about immortality, but I ain't seen it.
听说精神能永垂不朽 不过我没见过
I wondered how it'd be when I died.
不知道我死时会怎样
What it'd be like to know that this breath now was the last one you was ever gonna draw.
当你知道那是最后一口气不知道是什么感觉
I just hope I can meet it the same way she did.
我希望能和她一样坦然面对
With the same... calm.
跟她一样...平静
Cos that's where it's hidden - the immortality I hadn't seen.
当心灵得到平静精神就能永垂不朽
Kids around here never fight.
这里的小孩不会打架
Sometimes.
有时候会
Sometimes when you see them playing
他们在玩耍的时候
they always fight!
总是会打架
- Is she afraid of me? - Little bit.
- 他怕我吗? - 有一点
- Are you afraid of me? - Yes.
- 你怕我吗? - 怕
- Why? - Cos you look...
- 为什么? - 因为你看起来...
You look as an army!
...像是个军人
- I look army? - Yes.
- 我像军人? - 对
Well, that don't matter.
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
这不重要
- Baby's tired. - Yes.
- 孩子累了 - 对
If she swims, she wants, she will sleep.
他游累了就会睡
All right, come on. Turn around.
好 来
Go, go, go, go. Go!
快...快...快
Come on, go.
快点...快点...
Go, go, go, go!
快 快 快
Witt, patrol boat!She's American.
威特 是美军的巡逻艇
What's it doing out here all alone?
它怎么会单独出现?
You haven't changed at all, have you, Witt?
威特 你一点都没变
You haven't learned a thing.
什么也没学到
All a man has to do is leave it to you, you'll put your head in the noose for him.
当别人信任你你就肯为他赴汤蹈火
How many times you been AWOL?
你逃过几年兵?
Been in the army, what? Six years now?
你当兵六年了
Ain't it time you smartened up and stopped being such a punk recruit?
如果要学聪明
I mean, if you're ever gonna.
现在该是时候了
We can't all be smart.
我们不能都当聪明人
No, we can't, and that's a shame.
没错 真可惜
Look at you.
看看你
Truth is, you can't take straight duty in my company.
你在我的连队不能乖乖服役
You'll never be a real soldier, not in God's world.
你在这世上不能成为 一个好的军人
This is C Company, of which I'm First Sergeant. I run this outfit.
这是C连 我是副连长
Captain Staros, he's the CO, but I'm the guy who runs it. Nobody's gonna foul that up.
史塔洛上尉是连长 这里是我话事 任何人都不可以违抗
You're just another mouth for me to feed.
你只是一张吃饭的嘴
Normally, you'd be court-martialled.
你本来要接受军事审判
But I worked a deal for ya.
算你好运
Gotta consider yourself lucky.
我给你另作安排
I'm sending you to a disciplinary outfit.
我派你到纪律部队
You'll be a stretcher-bearer. You'll be taking care of the wounded.
当担架兵 照顾伤兵
I can take anything you dish out.
我能接受任何处罚
I'm twice the man you are.
我一个人就比你好两倍
In this world...
在这个世界里
a man himself is nothing.
一个人根本微不足道
And there ain't no world but this one.
只有这一个世界
You're wrong there, Top.
你错了 副连长
I seen another world.
我见过另一个世界
Sometimes I think it was just... my imagination.
有时候我觉得这只是我的想像
Well,
好
then you've seen things I never will.
我和你的看法不同
We're living in a world that's blowing itself to hell as fast as everybody can arrange it.
这个世界在自我毁灭
In a situation like that all a man can do is shut his eyes and let nothing touch him.
你只以只眼开只眼闭
Look out for himself.
为自己着想
I might be the best friend you ever had.
我可能是你最好的朋友
You don't even know it.
你自己都不知道
He hates you worse than poison.
他憎死你了
I never felt he hated me, cos I don't hate him.
我不觉得他憎我 因为我不憎他
I love Charlie Company.
我爱C队的兄弟
They're my people.
他们是我的家人
They call it "The Rock".
这个岛叫"顽石"
Nobody wants this island. Japs just put an airfield there.
原本无人占领 后来让日军盖了机场
Fighting's confined to this area.
主要战区在这里
This is their road to Australia, and this is their way of controlling the sea lanes to America.
这是攻击澳洲的途径亦是进攻美国的海道
If we're gonna stop the Japs' advance into the South Pacific, we've gotta do it right there.
若要阻止日军攻占南太平洋 就得在这里开战
The Marines have done their job. Now it's our turn.
海军陆战队已经试过 现在轮到我们
Worked my ass off.
我们将奋不顾身
Brown-nosed the generals.
尽量迎合将军
Degraded myself
降低身份
for them and my family.
为他们 为我家人
For my home.
和我的家
- I admire you, Colonel. I do. - Thank you, sir.
- 我很敬佩你 上校 - 谢谢你 长官
Most men your age would have retired by now.
你这年纪的军官早已退休了
It's OK.
你是好军人
We need general officers with maturity and character like you.
部队需要你这种成熟的长官
We've got good sergeants and good lieutenant colonels.
我们有好的中士和中校
But once a man gets those eagles, he can't wait to get that star.
他们一当了上校 就想做将军
He becomes a politician, right?
于是成为政客
Goes along to get along.
只会拍上司的马屁
So goddamn hard to stay upright.
很难坚持原则
- You said it there, sir. - With the Admiral watching, which he will be.
- 你说得对 长官 - 上将会注意我的表现
- There's always someone watching. - Yeah.
- 一定有人盯着你 - 嗯
Like a hawk.
像只猎鹰
Always someone ready to jump in, if you're not.
总是有人想抢你的功劳
- D'you have a son, Colonel? - Yes, sir.
- 你有儿子吗 上校? - 有的 长官
Good. We don't want our sons or grandsons fighting this war 30 years from now, do we?
很好 不能让子孙打这场烂仗
- No, sir, we sure don't. - Then you crush 'em without mercy.
- 没错 是不能 - 那就全力攻敌
You dig them out of the hills and protect that airfield.
把敌人赶尽杀绝 抢下机场
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
You wonder why... Why did the Japs put an airfield there of all places?
你有没有想过日军为何在这儿盖机场?
I guess we don't know the bigger picture, if there is such a thing.
我们对大局不太清楚
- What do you think? - Well, sir, I never ask myself that question.
- 你认为呢? - 我从不想这种问题
You're a humble man.
你很谦虚
Nobody wants that island... but you.
没人要这座岛...除了你
How much do you want it?
你有多大的决心?
As much as I have to, sir.
我会全力以赴
All they sacrificed for me
家人为我做的牺牲
poured out like water on the ground.
就像覆水难收
All I might have given for love's sake.
我本来能好好爱他们
Too late.
太迟了
Died...
我的心已死
slow as a tree.
像树木一样慢慢凋零
D'you feel it?
你感觉得到吗?
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
The closer you are to Caesar, the greater the fear.
权力越大 恐惧越深
I just can't help how damn scared I am, sarge, all right?
我就是感到害怕
I can't help it. I got...
无法控制
My stepdaddy took a block and beat me when I was real little
小时候我继父常用砖块打我
and I was scared and I used to run, I used to hide.
我好怕 老是躲起来
Hell, I slept in the chicken coop a whole lot of nights.
时常睡在鸡窝
And I never thought it'd get no worse than that.
我以为我不会再害怕
But I'm living by the... by the minute here. I'm counting the seconds.
但是现在我分秒都在害怕
Hell, we're gonna be landing soon and there's gonna be air raids.
马上就要登陆一定会遭到空袭
We're probably gonna die before we get off the beach.
我们会阵亡在滩头
This place is... It's like a big floating graveyard.
这艘船就像漂流的坟墓
- What's your name, kid? - I wanna own an automobile when I get out.
- 你叫什么 小子? - 我退伍后想买一辆车
- What's your name? - Edward, Edward B Train.
- 你叫什么? - 爱德华崔恩
Train?
崔恩?
The only things that are permanent is, is dying and the Lord. That's it.
只有上帝和死亡是永恒的
That's all you gotta worry about. This war ain't... gonna be the end of me or you neither.
我只担心这些 这场战争不是你我的终点
- Think we'll catch an air raid? - How in the hell should I know?
- 会遇到空袭吗? - 我怎么知道?
All's I know are them crew guys said they didn't catch no air raid the last time.
别的大兵说上次进攻就没有
On the other hand, time before last they nearly got blew up.
上上一次他们差点被炸死
What d'you want me to tell you?
你要我怎么说
You're a big help, Tills. Nothing. Tell me nothing.
多谢了 你什么也没说
Tell you something.
不过我要告诉你
We're sitting out here on this ocean like a couple of fuckin' ducks in these boats.
我们在船上就像是死鸭子
I already know that.
我早就知道
Well, brood on it, Tills.
好好想一想 提奥
Brood on it.
好好地想
- Ain't you watching the fun? - I ain't interested.
- 不看好戏吗? - 没兴趣
- Yeah, I guess it is pretty crowded. - Wouldn't be interested, even if it wasn't.
- 太迫了 - 就算不迫我也不想看
Well, I'm on my way to get me that pistol.
我要去拿那把手枪
Yeah? Well, have fun.
是吗? 开心点
Yeah, have fun.
是啊 开心点
You'll wish you had one once we get ashore and run into some of them samurai sabres.
有手枪才能对付日本武士刀
Open this door! Open this goddamn door!
快开门 给我开门...
Open the door!
快开门
I never bargained for nothing like this when I signed up for this man's army before the war.
我入伍时没想到会有这下场
How was I supposed to know there was gonna be a fuckin' war, huh? Answer me that.
我怎么知道会打仗? 你倒是说说
All I know is Charlie Company's always getting screwed. Always.
我只知道C连最衰了
And I can tell you whose fault it is, too.
我也知道是谁的错
It's that captain of ours.
就是我们的连长
First he gets us stuck off on this boat where we don't know a fucking soul.
他害大家被派上这艘鬼船
Then he gets us stuck way down in fourth place on the list to get off this son of a bitch.
而且是第四批登陆部队
Hello, Captain.
连长 你好
I read in your 201 file that you were an officer before the war.
档案说你在战前是军官
How'd you end up a private?
怎么会变成二等兵?
Cos of my wife.
因为我太太
I was in the corps of engineers.
我本来在工兵部队
We'd never been separated before,
我和她从来没分开过
not even for a night.
连一晚都没有
I took it for four months and then I quit.
我忍受了四个月最后终于放弃
Just resigned.
辞职不干
They sent me back to the States.
我被送回美国
They told me I'd never get another commission.
永远不能当军官
They said they'd see to it I got drafted and that I for damn sure'd be in the infantry.
他们说要徵召我入伍让我当步兵
Sons of bitches.
那些浑蛋
No, I don't blame them.
我不怪他们
Well, where is she now?
她在哪里?
She's home.
在家里
Why should i be afraid to die?
我并不怕死
I belong to you.
因为我已属于你
Move! Move! Move!
快...快...快...
Move! Move!
快 快
快点...
Moving out!
快 快
If i go first, I'll wait for you there.
如果我先走 我会等你的
On the otherside of the dark waters.
就在死亡的另一边
Put your helmet on.
贝尔 戴上头盔
Be with me now.
你与我同在
- Feeling the pressure, Captain? - Yes, sir.
- 压力很大 对吧? - 是的 长官
I like you, Captain.
我喜欢你 上尉
And I just want you to know, well, we're in this thing together. All right?
我要你知道我很支持你
Keep pressing inland till you reach the line. I'll catch up with you there.
你先逼近敌区 我会赶上来
- Yes, sir. - It's all yours, Captain.
- 是的 长官 - 由你全权指挥
Gangway! Gangway there!
让开 让开
Coming through!
我要过去
Squad leaders! Both teams!
班长马上报到
This way, son. This way, right here.
在这里
Stand by to go over the side!
准备上登陆船
Our Father, who art in heaven...
我们在天上的父
And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors.
免我们的债如同我们免人的债
For Thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory.
国度权柄荣耀全是您的 阿们
Your outfit's lucky.
你们很幸运
Transports must've been spotted.
运输船刚被日军发现
You're getting outta here just ahead of time.
幸好你们下来了
Take a breath, mister. You gotta breathe!
深呼吸 你得深呼吸
- You Charlie Company? - Yeah.
- 这是C连吗? - 是的
We went in a mile. Nothing there.
我们深入内陆一英里 什么也没有
Some oil drums. There'd be nothing there for...
一个礼拜都没动静
- A week. - A week, sir.
- 一个礼拜 - 一个礼拜 长官
No casualties. Japs must've hauled ass.
无人伤亡 日军大概都跑了
Two mortars hit the beach, but most guys came in standing up.
我们受迫击炮攻击 无人伤亡
Darnedest thing I ever did see.
这地方很不可思议
They got fish that live in trees.
还有鱼住在树上
If they didn't know this beach was deserted, what else don't they know?
指挥部好像没搞清楚状况
Who are you to live in all these many forms?
您化身为宇宙万物
Your death that captures all.
万物皆难逃一死
You, too, are the source of all that's gonna be born.
您也是生命的泉源
Your glory.
您充满荣耀
Mercy.
慈悲
Peace.
宁静
Truth.
真理
You give calm a spirit,
您能安抚人心
understanding,
给人们谅解
courage.
和勇气
The contented heart.
使人得到满足
Get a medic here!
医务兵 这里
Maybe all men got one big soul who everybody's a part of.
也许每个人都有共同的灵魂 和相同的命运
All faces of the same man.
每张脸孔都是同一个人
One big self.
一个大我
Everyone looking for salvation by himself.
每个人都想获得救赎
Each like a coal drawn from the fire.
像炭火般燃烧生命
We're going straight up that hill there.
我们要攻上那座山头
- We can't do that, Colonel. - Well, there's no way to outflank it.
- 办不到 上校 - 我们无法包抄敌军
On the left is a cliff that falls down into the river.
左边的悬崖底下是河流
The Japanese hold the jungle. It has to be taken frontally.
日军守住丛林 我们得正面突袭
What about water, sir? It's not getting up here.
食水怎么办? 山上没清水
My men are... passing out, sir.
我的兄弟都因为脱水昏倒
Only time you worry about a soldier is when he stops bitching.
他们能发牢骚就能打仗
We're all gonna attack abreast. Third Platoon in reserve.
并肩前进 第三排留守
We've gotta cross those three folds of ground. You see?
我们得越过三个山丘
Once we get beyond that, we gotta attack that hill.
然后再攻下山头
Colonel says there's no way to outflank it, so we gotta take it head-on by frontal assault.
上校说不能采取包抄攻势 我们得正面突袭
- Whyte? - Yeah?
- 伟特 - 是
- See the grassy ridges at the foot of that hill? - Yeah.
- 看到山坡前面吗? - 看到了
When you get to the end of that field, eliminate all strong points on those ridges.
等你攻上山坡 找到敌军据点然后消灭他们
I'm sure the Japs got something there to protect the approaches.
那儿一定有敌军守住
Are you here?
主啊 您在吗?
Let me not betray you.
别让我背叛您
Let me not betray my men.
别让我背叛我的兄弟
In you I place my trust.
您让我充满信心 和希望
(希腊语)
Rosy-fingered dawn.
玫瑰般的黎明
You're Greek, aren't you, Captain?
你是希腊人
D'you ever read Homer?
读过荷马的史诗吗?
We read Homer at the Point.In Greek.
我在西点军校读过希腊原文
What kind of artillery support do we have, sir? Over.
有多少炮兵支援火力?
- Two batteries of 105s. - They won't make a dent. Over.
- 两组105榴弹炮 - 一点都没有用
No, but it bucks the men up. It'll look like the Japs are catching hell.
不过能提高士气 日军会被炸得很难看
OK, you guys.
兄弟们
This is it.
准备上吧
We're going down in groups often.
每组十人攻上山头
There's no point in going by rushes. Only make a better target stopped, so...
快速前进才不会成为目标
run all the way.
一路跑上去
We ain't got no choice. We're picked, so we gotta go.
我们被选上 别无选择 非去不可
I'm gonna take the first bunch myself.
我亲自带领先锋队
I want Charlie Dale with me. Dale?
我要戴尔跟着我 戴尔?
You go organise them guys that's up there.
叫兄弟在山坡集合
Moving out in five minutes.
五分钟后出发
Let's go.
走吧
Sico?
施高?
- What's wrong with you? - I'm sick to my stomach.
- 你怎么了? - 我的肚子好痛
Sico, you get up now, or I'll kick you so hard you're gonna be sick.
起来 小心我踢扁你
I can't. I would if I could.
我站不起来
I'm sick.
我生病了
我病了
You ain't sick. Get up!
你没有病 起来
- What's the matter, Sico? - I don't know, Sergeant.
- 施高 怎么了? - 不晓得
It's my stomach. I'm in pain, I got cramps.
肚子好痛 好像是胃痉孪
I can't even sit up straight. I'm sick.
我病了 坐不起来
- Come on, get up! - Leave him.
- 给我起来! - 别逼他了
I need a volunteer to carry the BAR! Drop your gear. I'm taking you to the medics.
谁要替我拿步枪? 我带你找医官
Thank you, Sergeant.
谢谢你 副连长
Don't argue with me.
别跟我争
Good luck, Keck.
祝好运 杰克
Maybe they pulled out.
也许他们撤退了
Hit dirt!
快趴下!
趴下来!
Calm down, calm down, calm down, calm down.
冷静点...冷静点...
Stretcher-bearers!
担架兵
Come on!
这儿
Stretcher-bearers, this way!
担架兵 在这儿
- Go get that man. - We already got eight or nine down there...
- 去救那兄弟 - 已经有八 九名伤兵...
- Don't argue with me! Get that man! - He's not the one we should think about...
- 别跟我争 我要救他 - 管不了他们了
Goddamn it, all of you! Am I in command here or am I not?!
该死 全都要救 我是指挥官
- Am I the captain or a goddamn private? - Others are hit bad. That's all I meant.
- 难道你是连长吗? - 我只是说别人伤得更重
- I gave you an order, private! - Yes, sir!
- 二兵 听我的命令 - 是 长官!
Hello, First Sergeant.
你好 副连长
Who we going after over here?
我们要救谁?
We think it's Jacques.
应该是积克
Ol' Jockey.
积克老兄
Well, shit. That's, that's, that's too bad.
真是倒霉
Sir?
长官?
Sir? Sir, can I come back to the company after we get Jockey back to the battalion?
把积克抬回去我能回来吗?
- OK, but you gotta get permission. - Sure. And my rifle.
- 好 你要得到许可 - 当然 我的步枪
Nicky! You're still alive!
力奇 你还活着
Keep moving! Keep moving!
继续前进! 继续前进!
Magnificent, Staros, magnificent. The finest thing these old eyes have seen in a long time!
太好了 史塔奥 好久没见到这么猛烈的攻击
Beautifully conceived and executed! You'll be mentioned in battalion orders.
你指挥得很好 我会请营长给你功勋
Young Whyte led beautifully.
伟特排长的表现也很棒
Yes, sir. Over.
是 长官
But sending in your second too was brilliant.
派第二排增援也很聪明
They may have carried the ridge. I don't think they were hurt too bad. Blane led well, too.
就快攻上去了 伤亡不惨重 布兰也不错
Now, how many emplacements did they locate?
他们发现多少据点?
Did they knock any out?
消灭了多少?
We ought to have those ridges cleaned out by noon! Over.
中午就应该能攻上山头
Hello! Hello! Staros, are you there?
史塔奥 你在吗?
Here, sir. Over.
我在 长官
I said, how many emplacements did they locate? Did they knock any out? Over.
他们发现多少据点? 消灭了多少?
Children.
孩子们
I don't know, sir.
我不知道
What the hell do you mean, you don't know? How can you not know? Over.
什么意思? 你怎么会不知道?
I'm right here behind the first swell, sir. I'm right here behind the swell.
我在第一座山丘后面
You want me to stand up and wave? Over.
要我站起来招手吗?
No, I can see where you are. I want you to do something.
我看到了 你得想办法
I want you to get up there and see what the situation is.
快上去看看情况如何
I want Hill 210 in my hands tonight.
今晚我就要你攻下山头
Now, goddamn it, the Admiral got up at dawn for this!
上将一早就要来查看
Come to life up there, Staros. Out!
提起精神来 史塔奥
Move up!
上来
Hey, Keck!
嘿 杰克!
Yeah?
干嘛?
- We gotta get out of here. - I know it.
- 我们得撤退 - 我知道
Blane's dead.
布兰死了
You're in charge.
你得指挥
We know you there, Yank!
美国佬 我们看到你们
Tojo eats shit!
东条英机去死
No! Roosevelt eats shit!
罗斯福去死
I got him! I got him!
我打到他了 我打到他了
I killed a man.
我杀死一个人
Hey, Queen!
嘿 昆恩!
Queen, you there?
昆恩 你在吗?
Worst thing you can do. Worse than rape.
杀人比强奸更严重
Queen! You see them Japs leaving that left ridge?
看到日本鬼子离开左边吗?
- I killed a man. Nobody can touch me for it. - I ain't seen nothing.
- 没有人能把我怎样 - 我什么也没看到
Well, get your fuckin' head up and look around!
抬起头来看看
I'm serious!
我是说真的!
I counted seven Japs leaving that left-hand grassy ridge!
有七个日兵离开左边
I got me one of 'em.
我打中一个
So?
又怎样?
I think maybe they're pulling out.
他们可能会撤退
Maybe somebody ought to go tell the captain.
也许该去告诉连长
You wanna be the one to do it?
你想去吗?
You just stay put! I'm ordering you!
我命令你别乱动
Down!
趴低
Stay low.
趴低点
Go! Go!
冲! 冲!
What do we do now?
现在怎么办?
We wait right here. Maybe they'll send us up some reinforcements.
在这儿等 也许会有人来支援
To do what?
做什么?
To capture some of these fucking positions around here!
攻下敌军的据点呀
- You mean you really wanna go on with this? - Hell, no. No, not no uphill charge.
- 你要继续进攻? - 不知道 不能直接进攻山头
If they send us reinforcements, maybe we could scout around
不过如果有支援
and locate these machine guns.
就能试着除掉机关枪
- Anyway, it's better than going back down. - Something's coming!
- 总比冒死退回去好 - 有人来了
They're coming!
他们来了!
What are they doin'?
他们在干什么?
If they want to throw us out, why didn't they come in force?
他们为什么不全力进攻?
Maybe they was acting on their own.
也许他们落了单
Maybe they wanted to get into nirvana.
也许他们想上西天
They're coming.
敌人来了
Keck!
怎么回事?
Jesus!
天啊
Oh, Jesus!
老天!
I blew my butt off!
我炸到屁股!
- It's all right. It's all right. - I blew my butt off!
- 没事 没事 - 我把屁股炸掉了
Lay down!
趴下来
What a fucking recruit trick to pull!
我怎么会这么衰?
- Take it easy. Take it easy. - I grabbed it by the pin!
- 我只拔到保险制 - 写信给我老婆
You write my old lady. You tell her... I want her to know I died like a man.
告诉她我死得很光荣
Nobody's gonna have to write her. You'll make it.
你不会死的 没人给她写 得你自己来
- Don't bullshit me! - Stay down!
- 别骗我 - 下来
Hey, hey.
嘿 嘿
Have I got mud on my face?
我全身是泥
Wipe it off. Get it off.
帮我擦掉
No!
不
I'll write her. I promise.
我会写信给她
Take my canteen. There's still some water in there.
我的水壶还有水 拿去吧
It's for the best.
也许这样最好
I'm all messed up down there.
我的下面被炸烂
I can't fuck no more.
不能搞了
Whoa... Where am I?
我在哪儿?
Where am I?
You're gonna be all right.
你不会有事
Even if you die, you didn't let your brother down.
就算你死了 你没有对不起兄弟
If you hadn't thrown yourself against that embankment, we'd all have been killed.
要是你不扑上去 我们全都会死
I'm cold.
我好冷
I'm... freezing.
我快冻死了
You gonna write his wife?
你要写信给他老婆?
Fuck, no.
才不要
I don't know his old lady.
我又不认识她
That's the company commander's job. You outta your mind? I ain't no good at writing.
那是连长的事 别傻了 我不会写信
You told him you would.
你答应过他
I'll say anything to 'em when they're like that.
他快死了 我得那么说
Somebody ought to do it.
有人得写信给她
Well, then, you write her. Yeah, you write her.
你写给她吧
What's wrong, Jim?
怎么回事?
There's nothing anybody can do for him. He'll die before they get him to a surgeon.
他没救了 谁也救不了他
- Then I can't ask you to go out there. - Maybe I could get some morphine into him.
- 你不必去了 - 我可以替他注射吗啡
- Would it keep him quiet? - Not for long, but I can give him two.
- 能让他安静吗? - 不能 我可以打两针
And I could maybe leave him three or four for himself.
留三 四针给他自己打
Couldn't you give 'em to him all at once?
你能一次打完吗?
That's what you are.
你们都会死
That's all there is for us. That's us, that's us.
我们全都会没命
I lost all twelve. I lost all twelve.
我的十二名弟兄都死了
All twelve of 'em.
全都挂了
It's insanity up there.
太疯狂了
I told 'em what to do, I showed 'em where to go and I gave 'em a push.
我叫他们勇往直前
- Somebody help! - I know you. I know you, Sergeant.
- 救命 - 我认得你...副连长
It's insane. I don't know who's in charge here, but don't let him go! Don't let him go!
这里谁指挥? 别放走他
I'm outta here. I'm outta here.
我要走 我要走
I'm outta here. All right, move feet. Move, move, move, move. Move, move!
两只脚 快走 走啊
I'm moving. I'm moving. I'm moving now.
我要走了 我要走了...
Don't touch. Don't touch. Don't look at me. Don't touch. OK, I'm outta here.
别碰我 别看我 别碰我 别看我 我走了
All right. All right.
没事了 没事了
Somebody help me!
救救我
Help me!
救救我!
You gotta be quiet. I came to help you, Tella.
还好吧 小子? 我来救你了 提拉
- OK. Calm down. - Fuck you!
- 安静点 - 去你的
I'm dying! I'm dying, sarge!
我快死了 我快死了
OK. Well, goddamn it, do it with less noise!
那就安静地等死
- How you gonna get me out? - I'm gonna take you back.
- 你能救我吗? - 我会带你回去
- Come on. - No!
- 来 - 不!
Put me down! Put me down!
放我下来 放我下来
Leave me alone... Leave me alone.
别管我 你别管我
Please, leave me alone.
你别管我
Give me more. Give me more.
给我多一点 给我多一点
再给我多一点...
Give me more. Give me more.
Here, Tella.
来吧
Goodbye... goodbye.
再见...再见...
Bye, kid.
再见了 小子
Goodbye, sarge. Goodbye.
再见 副连长
Fortunately, Jim, the fate of the company doesn't depend on one man.
幸好部队不必只靠一个大兵
Sergeant, I saw the whole thing through the glasses.
我用望远镜看到经过
I'm gonna mention you in orders tomorrow and recommend you for the Silver Star.
我会请营长表扬你
- It's the most courageous thing... - Captain,
- 我要替你争取银星勋章 - 长官
you say one more word to thank me, I'll knock you right in the teeth.
你再说下去我就把你揍扁
You mention me in your fuckin' orders, and I'll resign so fast
你去争取勋章 我马上辞职
and leave you here to run this busted-up outfit by yourself.
让你一个人指挥这个烂部队
You understand?
懂不懂?
Property! Whole fuckin' thing's about property.
权力! 打仗全是为了权力
What's the matter with you, Staros? Those men should be reinforced immediately!
你在搞什么鬼? 马上派人支援他们
What are they doing? I can see 'em through my glasses.
他们在干嘛?
They're lying behind that ledge!
躲在那里做什么?
They should be up and out, cleaning out those machine guns! Over!
他们应该去消灭机关枪
I don't think you understand what's going on, sir.
我想你不明白 长官
We've had... heavy casualties.
我们的伤亡惨重
We had a man... His gut got shot out on the slopes, sir. Created quite an upset.
有一个人的肠子被打出来 死得很惨
Fine, fine. Now, what about those reinforcements? Over.
好吧 到底有没有支援?
I have two squads to First Platoon I can send up, sir. Over.
第一排有两个班可以支援
What the hell do you mean, two squads?!
什么 两个班?!
Goddamn you, Staros! When I say reinforcements,
该死 我叫你支援就照办
goddamn it, I mean it! You commit everybody you have there and do it now!
马上派全体兄弟攻上去
Your First Platoon, too. I see 'em lying on their fat asses doing nothing.
第一排也得去 我看到他们躺着不动
Get a man to 'em right now with orders to attack, and move 'em by the flank to the ridge.
派人上去 命令他们进攻 命令他们侧攻
Then get that Second Platoon over to the hill!
然后叫第二排攻上山头
Have 'em press the centre. Go straight up that goddamn hill!
叫他们直接攻上去
Attack them right now!
马上进攻
Jesus, Staros! Do i have to give you a lesson on infantry tactics
天啊 要我教吗?
while your men are getting their asses shot off?.
你的兄弟快被射死了
Colonel, I don't think you fully understand what is going on here.
上校 你不明白这里的情况
My company alone cannot take that position, sir.
光凭这一队不能攻下山头
The Japs are too well dug in. They've got too much fire power.
敌军防守严密 火力太强
Colonel, there's a bunker up there.
上面有座碉堡
We can't see it, and it's... it's chewing my men to pieces, sir.
我们看不到 它把我的兄弟打得很惨
I request permission for patrol reconnaissance around
请你准许我先派人
to the right of Hill 210. I believe the entire position, sir,
进入右边的森林搜查
can be outflanked with a manoeuvre there in force.
从右边包抄应该能攻下山头
- No! Goddamn it, no! - Might save lives!
- 不行 该死 - 挽救生命
There'll be no flanking move.
不能包抄
Listen, Staros. You're not gonna take your men
听我说 你不能带兄弟
around into the jungle to avoid a goddamn fight!
躲到丛林当缩头乌龟
Do you hear me, Staros? I want you to attack right now with every man at your disposal!
我要你带领兄弟全力进攻
Now, attack, Staros! That's a direct order!
史塔奥 快进攻 这是命令
Sir, I must tell you that I refuse to obey your order.
我必须违背你的命令
- There it is, right there. See it? - I don't see it.
- 在那里 能看见吗? - 看不见
This is not your fault, Jim. He's ordering you to.
你没有错 他下了命令
I again request permission for patrol reconnaissance around to the right in force.
我请你让我派人到丛林搜查
The time, sir,... is 1321 hours, 25 seconds.
现在时间是...13时21分25秒
I have two witnesses here. I request that you do the same with witnesses there. Over.
两名证人听到我的话 请你也找证人
Staros, don't pull this guardhouse-lawyer bullshit with me!
别给我来律师那一套
Now, I know you're a goddamn lawyer! This is not a court of law.
你是律师 这里却不是法庭
This is a war. It's a goddamn battle!
这是战场 我们在打仗
Now, I want that frontal attack. I repeat my order. Over.
我重覆 我要你正面攻击
Colonel, I refuse to take my men up there in a frontal attack.
我拒绝率领兄弟作正面攻击
It's suicide, sir.
这等于是自杀
I've lived with these men for two years, and I will not order them all to their deaths. Over.
我和他们生活两年半 不能命令他们送死 完毕
This is a very important decision, Staros.
这是很重大的决定
But if you feel that strongly, maybe you have a reason, so I'm coming down.
也许你有理由这么做
Go take a look.
我要过去
I'm not rescinding my order to you, son,
我不是取消命令
but if I find extenuating circumstances when I get there, I'll take that into account.
不过如果是特殊状况 我会仔细考虑
Now, in the meantime, goddamn it, I want you to hold on until I get there.
你们守在那儿等我来
And, if possible, you get those men on the ridge out and moving! Out.
可能的话叫那些兄弟前进 完毕
(希腊语)
One spot's as good as another, men.
哪里都一样
There's no place to hide.
根本就无处可躲
Just take it easy, son. Take it easy. Take it easy.
孩子 放松点
Where's... where's Fife?
费夫呢?
Fife? He's right here, son. Fife.
在这儿 费夫
Hold my hand, Fife.
握住我的手
Hold my hand.
握我的手
I got it.
抓住了
I'm dying, Fife.
我快死了
Oh, Captain...
连长...
Shut up in a tomb.
我被埋在棺材里
Can't lift the lid.
掀不起棺盖
Played a role I never conceived.
我的处境进退两难
Get that blouse on, soldier. It's not a goddamn bathing beach!
穿上衣服 这不是海滩
Put it on right now.
立刻穿上
What you aiming at, son? Let's go get those son of a bitches.
你在指谁? 去杀敌呀
Move up!
前进!
What are you doing laying down there where you can't see a damn thing?
你趴在这儿什么也看不到
Observing, sir. Just sent First Platoon forward to the ridge.
我正在观察 我派第一排上去
- How many of 'em were hit this time? - None, sir.
- 这次有几个中弹? - 没有
None? Not one?
一个都没有?
Doesn't sound like the situation you described to me over the sound power.
这跟你说的情况不一样
Well, it's not. The situation's changed just in the last five minutes, sir.
五分钟前情况改变了
Captain, you listen to me.
上尉 给我听住
We're going over there and taking everybody with us.
我们要全力向前进攻
Do you have any more complaints or demurrers?
有问题吗?
- No, sir. Not now. - All right! We're gonna do things my way!
- 现在 没有 - 好吧 你得照我的方法
My way! You understand that, Captain?
让我来指挥
We're taking everybody over to that ledge! We may take that ridge by nightfall!
大家上去 晚上得攻下来
I think the ridge is quite a way from being reduced, sir.
上面的火力还是很强
Show me how to see things the way you do.
神啊 你到底看到什么?
让我知道你看到什么
We're just dirt. We're just dirt.
我们全是尘土
We're gonna get killed if we stay here.
留在这儿肯定送命
Bell, take six men
比尔 带六个弟兄
and go see what's up there.
上去探查
And we'll cover you the best we can from down there.
我们会掩护你们
OK.
好
You guys, you guys, stay here. OK?
你们留下来
I'm going alone.
我一个人去
Come out.
来吧
Come out where lam.
到我的身边
There was a... There was a...
上面有...上面有...
There's a bunker... up there.
上面有一座碉堡
It's five guns.
总共有五支机关枪
五支机关枪
That strongpoint up there, somewhere up there around those rocks,
攻下那些乱石间的碉堡
is the key to this ridge.
就能攻下这座山头
Bell here is quite right.
比尔说得没错
From their knob up there, those little brown brothers can cover the whole of the ground
日本鬼子从上面
in front of this position for 1,000 yards. They've left this ledge unguarded.
可以扫射一千码内的目标 不过他们漏掉这地方
Now, goddamn it, that's a mistake. That's a hell of a mistake.
这是很严重的错误 这是很严重的错误
We need to take advantage of it before they see their error.
我们得利用他们的疏忽
All right, all right, I know you're all pretty exhausted,
我知道你们筋疲力尽
and we've had a hell of a time getting water up here.
这里连清水也没有
For that I'm sorry. I apologise to you all.
对不起 我向大家道歉
But if we can reduce this bunker tomorrow, I think we can take this ridge.
不过明天若能攻下这座碉堡 就能占领山头
So I'm asking for volunteers.
有没有人自愿
Go back up there and knock it out.
回去攻下那座碉堡
Sir?
长官
I'll be glad to go back up
我愿意...
- and lead the way back for a party. - Right.
- 身先士卒回去作战 - 很好 比尔
- I'll go, sir. - You.
- 上校 我也去 - 还有你
All right.
好的
- I'd like to lead the party, Colonel. - All right, John. I was hoping you'd say that.
- 我很想率领突击队 - 我正希望你去 约翰
- You'll be in command. - I'll go, sir.
- 你来指挥 - 我要去
- Sir? - You.
- 长官 - 你
All right, men, that's enough. Seven is plenty. Gather up.
够了 七个人够多了 准备出发
I don't know if you realise the importance of this operation, Staros.
史塔奥 你知道这一役有多重要吗?
Once our position is secured, we can move the bombers in.
攻下这座岛 轰炸机就能降落
That means air power for 1,000 miles in every direction.
我们的军队 便有一千英里的空中攻击力
Guadalcanal may be the turning point in the war.
窝达康拉尔岛一役能决定胜负
- It'll cost lives. Is that what's troubling you? - No, sir.
- 你不同意 一定得牺牲性命? - 不是 长官
I explained to you the importance of this objective.
我跟你说过胜利的重要
How many men do you think it's worth? How many lives?
你认为牺牲多少兄弟才值得?
I can't say, sir.
我不知道
Are you prepared to sacrifice the lives of any of your men in this campaign?
你愿意牺牲你的兄弟吗?
How many? One? Two?
多少? 一个? 两个?
Twenty?
二十个?
Lives will be lost in your company, Captain.
你的小队一定会死人
And if you don't have the stomach for it, now is the time to let me know.
要是你受不了 现在最好让我知道
No, sir. You're right... about everything you said.
不 你说得对 你说得都对
Fine, fine.
好吧 没事了
That's all, Captain.
好吧 长官
One more thing, Staros.
还有一件事
It's not necessary for you to ever tell me that you think I'm right.
你不必跟我说我说得对
Ever.
没有必要
We'll assume it.
这是理所当然的
Dismissed.
解散
I feel sorry for you, kid.
我为你感到遗憾
- Yeah? - Yeah, a little.
- 是吗? - 有一点吧
This army's gonna kill you.
这场仗会害死你
If you were smart, you'd take care of yourself. There's nothing you can do for anybody else.
你还是保佑自己好运点 别想救别人了
You're just running into a burning house where nobody can be saved.
就算你拼命也救不了什么人
What difference do you think you can make? One single man in all this madness.
在乱世中一个人的力量很渺小
If you die, it's gonna be for nothing.
不要白白送死
There's not some other world out there where everything's gonna be OK.
没有另一个美好世界
There's just this one.
这是唯一的世界
Just this rock.
只有这座孤岛
Go ahead! Come on, come on.
来吧 让我死吧
Who's deciding who's gonna live?
谁能决定别人的生?
Who's deciding who's gonna die?
谁能决定别人的死?
This is futile!
太荒谬了
Look at me! I stand right up here and not one bullet.
看看我 我身上没有中弹
Not one shot!
毫发未伤!
Why?
为什么?
How come they all had to die?
他们全都死了
I can stand right here, I can stand right up and nothing happens to me!
我却站在这儿 一点事也没有
We.
我们
We together.
我们在一起
One being.
合而为一
Flow together like water,
水乳交融
till I can't tell you from me.
分不出你和我
I drink you.
我爱你
Now.
现在
You're my light.
您是我的明灯
My guide.
我的指引
John, I'll be behind you. If you wanna break through, we'll come after.
我们在后面 要是攻破防线
We'll charge at your whistle signal.
就吹哨子通知我们冲上去
All right, let's go, men. Go get 'em.
去吧 去杀敌吧
OK.
好
Stay down, below this ledge,
你们留在底下
and I'll call down the data from above.
我从上面叫出敌人方位
Once the 81s have plastered that rock... as much as possible,
让炮兵密集轰炸这些岩石
we're gonna crawl out along that big rock for cover
再到大石旁找掩护
and then flank 'em to the right.
然后从右翼进攻
OK?
好吗?
OK. OK.
好...好
Azimuth 1470... from Easy Roger 7.
方位1470...座标ER7
100 left, add 200.
左方一百码 距离两百码
Uncle Baker 1, fire mission.
炮兵部队 准备开炮
Azimuth 1470 from Easy Roger 7.
方位1470 座标ER7
Left 100, add 200.
左方一百码 距离两百码
Machine gun. Will adjust. Over.
炮轰机关枪 稍后再修正
Understand. 1470 from EasyRoger 7.
收到了 方位1470 座标ER7
Left 25, drop 50!
左25码 前50码
Left 25, Uncle Baker 1.
炮兵部队
Left 25, drop 50.
左25码 前50码
Fire for effect. Over.
准备开炮
Roger, Uncle Baker 1.
收到 炮兵部队
Let's go!
上吧
OK, we're gonna continue on up the hill to the right.
从右翼攻上山头
Nobody fire or throw the grenades till I give the signal.
等我信号再开枪或丢手榴弹
OK, let's do it.
好 咱们上
Is he OK? ls he all right?
他没事吧?
What we gonna do? Can't take him with us.
不能把他带走 怎么办?
- No, we can't leave him here. - He's from your platoon. You stay with him.
- 不能把他留下来 - 你们是同队兄弟 你陪他
We can leave him and pick him up on the way back,... if he's still alive.
我们回来再接他...如果他还活着
- Is he dead? - Not yet.
- 他死了吗? - 还没有
Dale, stay with him! Cover our flank! Move!
陪着他 掩护我们 冲吧
Behind you!
小心后面
We're pinned down!
我们被打得好惨
Fall back!
撤退
Go!
走吧
Watch out.
小心
Clear!
安全了!
Come on. Get out.
给我滚出来
Go on.
出来
Think you're soldiers?
你想杀我们?
You piece of shit!
你这人渣
Son of a bitch!
狗娘养的
All right?
如何?
I shot a man.
我杀死一个人
Stinks around here.
这里好臭
- All these dead people. - Put a cigarette up your nose.
- 这么多死人 - 鼻孔里塞烟头
Look at 'em move!
看他们逃命!
We got 'em on the run!
把他们赶跑了
Way to go, John. When they saw you make that attack and win,
约翰 干得好 你把他们打得落花流水
you put their hearts back into them.
兄弟们都士气高涨
- Hey, hey! - Don't do that, soldier.
- 嘿 嘿 - 别打了
Take care of the others. G-2 will want them. There'll be somebody around before long.
把犯人带来 交给情报部 他们马上就来
We've wasted enough time here. Let's go.
浪费了很多时间 走吧
Sir, I've a few recommendations for decorations.
我要推荐一些人接受勋章
Yes. We'll get everything for all of 'em that we can, but later.
我会尽力向他们争取 但是迟些再说
Meantime, I want you to know I'm personally recommending you for something, John.
不过我要你知道 我会推荐你接受勋章
Perhaps the big one.
也许是英勇奖章
- Thank you, sir, but I don't feel... - Yes, you do, John.
-  谢谢你 不过我... - 这是你应得的
Getting it for you will be the goddamn problem!
能不能争取到才是问题
But, hell, it'd be a big thing for the battalion and the regiment, if you did get it.
你能受勋对部队有很大鼓舞
We better move out.
最好赶快前进
We need to extend our lines, hook up with the other companies and push on to the top.
加入别的部队攻上山头
Would you like to take command of Baker Company?
你想指挥B队吗?
Of course.
当然想
Sir, I don't mean to be a wet blanket, but about the water. If we don't get water...
我不想扫你的兴 但是没有食水...
Don't worry about water.
别担心水的问题
John, I don't want anything to break up this attack of ours now we have the momentum.
现在士气如虹 不能中断
We'll have some water in a... couple of hours.
过几个小时就有食用水
I've arranged for that.
我会安排的
Now, we just can't stop now, goddamn it, and wait for it.
该死 现在不能停下来
No, sir.
是的 长官
That's right.
没错
And if some of the men... pass out, why, hell, they'll just have to pass out.
如果有些人因脱水昏倒 那就让他们昏倒
All right.
好吧
They could...
他们会死的
They could die from it.They could die from enemy fire, too!
他们也会被敌人杀死
They're all tough boys.
他们很坚强
Come on, men, let's go! You'll see plenty more of those where we're going!
兄弟们 走吧 一路上会有更多死人
Are we going up this hill or aren't we?
到底要不要上山头?
John, I'm convinced that the Japanese position can be broken now.
我相信现在能突破日军防线
All we have to do is keep going and we'll have this hill. We'll have this hill by sundown.
只要继续前进 日落时就能攻下山头
You see the spirit in these men? D'you see the new spirit?
看到他们全新的斗志吗?
Well, I want to take advantage of that before something happens to sap their strength.
我们得一鼓作气 乘胜追击
To have this battalion relieved in a defeat,
要是稍微迟疑就会战败
or even to have it reinforced from troops from the reserves,if we were to stall before reaching the top, well,
或者是根本攻不上山头
Jesus Christ, that's just a hell of a lot more than I could stand!
天啊 我不能忍受失败
I've waited all my life for this.
我等了一辈子
I've worked, slaved, eaten... oh, untold buckets of shit to have this opportunity!
一直以来忍气吞声 都是为了这一刻
And I don't intend to give it up now.
我不会半途而废
You don't know what it feels like to be passed over.
你不知道被忽略的感受
I mean, you're young. You're just out of the Academy.
你刚出军校 还很年轻
You're, you know, you've got your war! This 15 years, this is my first war!
你生对时代了 我等了十五年才等到这场战争
John, some day you'll understand.
有一天你会了解
You're like a son to me, John.
我把你当儿子看待
You know what my son does?
知道我儿子做什么吗?
He's a bait salesman.
他做鱼饵生意
You've done a hell of a job, John.
你干得很好
I'm gonna make sure that you get everything, everything that you deserve.
我要让你得到应得的荣誉
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
God...
天啊...
Goddamn it! I want three runners!
该死 我要三名传令兵
Get me three runners!
给我三名传令兵
You go back to the rear to find water
回去找水源
and get back here with it as fast as you can!
马上运过来
We attack in one hour! We'll throw everything we got at 'em.
一小时后就全力进攻
We're going all the way! Nothing'll stop us.
不能失败 没人能阻止
It's high ground by nightfall!
晚上就得成功
You seen many dead people?
你看过死人吗?
Plenty.
很多
They're no different than dead dogs,
跟死狗没两样
once you get used to the idea.
只要有这种想法
They're meat, kid.
他们就像猪肉一样
Are you righteous? Kind?
你们代表正义和善良吗?
Does your confidence lie in this?
你们是否有信心?
Are you loved by all?
受到大家爱护?
Know that I was, too.
我跟你们一样
Do you imagine your sufferings will be less because you loved goodness?
你们认为自己所受的苦难 是比较少吗?
Truth?
我们善良有良知
Get fucking on the ground! Get down! Get down!
趴下来 趴下来
Get down. Stay there.
趴下来 呆着
Get on the ground! Get on the fucking ground!
给我趴下来 快点
Now!
快!
This great evil.
这么可怕的邪恶
Where's it come from?
它来自哪里?
How'd it steal into the world?
怎么会潜伏在世上?
What seed, what root did it grow from?
原因和根源到底是什么?
Who's doing this?
这是谁造成的?
Who's killing us?
谁在屠杀众生
Robbing us of life and light.
剥夺我们的生命之火
Mocking us with the sight of what we might have known.
嘲笑我们对人间的依恋
Does our ruin benefit the Earth?
战争对地球有利吗?
Does it help the grass to grow or the sun to shine?
它能滋长万物 孕育众生吗?
Is this darkness in you, too?
上帝也有黑暗的一面?
Have you passed through this night?
他是否也感受邪恶力量?
I'm gonna sink my teeth into your liver.
我要把你开膛剖肚
You're dying.
你死定了
See them birds up there?
看到那些鸟吗?
You know they eat you raw?
它们会把你生吞活剥
Where you're going, you're not coming back from.
你下地狱就回不来
(日语)
What are you to me?
你对我有意义吗?
Nothing.
毫无义意
Have a seat here.
坐下来
Staros, I'm relieving you of your command.
史塔奥 我要将你革职
Lieutenant Band will take over for you.
班中尉会取代你
I already told him.
我跟他说了
It's a hard thing to do.
我也不想这么做
Difficult decision to make.
这是很困难的决定
I don't think you're tough enough.
你的心不够狠
You're too soft. You're just too soft-hearted. You're not tough-fibred enough.
你心太软了 不够心狠手辣
Anyway, it's my decision to make. I've already made it.
我的心意已定 没什么好说
I don't like to see my men get killed, sir.
我不想让我的兄弟送死
Have you ever had anyone die in your arms, sir?
有人曾死在你怀里吗?
Have you?
有吗?
I don't see any reason to make a scandal out of this.
我不想引起事端
I don't want it in the records of the battalion. There's no reason for you to have it on yours.
也不想在服役记录中留下污点
This has nothing to do with cowardice or inefficiency.
这和能力或胆量无关
Look at this jungle.
看看这座丛林
Look at those vines, the way they twine around the trees, swallowing everything.
那些藤蔓缠绕着大树 吞食一切
Nature's cruel, Staros.
大自然很残酷
I'm going to let you apply for reassignment to the Judge Advocate General Corps
你可以申请调到华府的军法局
for reasons of ill health.
就说你生了病
You're a lawyer.
你是律师
- You had malaria yet? - No, I haven't.
- 你得过虐疾吗? - 没有
Doesn't matter. I can fix that.
无所谓 我会安排的
Anyway, you probably will have it.
反正你会染上的
I'm also recommending you for the Silver Star.
我也会推荐你获颁银星勋章
And I'll recommend it in such a way it definitely won't be refused.
我一定会让你无法推辞
Might as well have the Purple Heart, too.
干脆也让你得紫心奖章
Why?
为什么?
Because of that scratch on your face and because of those cuts on your hands.
因为你脸上的疤 和手上的伤口
Listen to me, Staros.
给我听好
I think it's best you go back with the next batch of wounded and prisoners.
你跟下一批伤兵离开
It is no goddamn good for you to keep hanging around.
留下来对你没好处
The quieter we keep this, the better it'll be for all.
这件事不说出去最好
This is from Colonel Tall.
这是多尔上校的宣布
"Our victory gives us the highest reasons for pride".
我们的胜利带来最高的荣耀
"It will prove a milestone in the battle for Guadalcanal".
这是窝达康拉尔岛役的转捩点
"Tomorrow the division commander will arrive to make an inspection of the line".
明天师长会亲自来检阅前线
"After the inspection we're to be relieved by a battalion of the division's reserve regiment".
接防部队会来换班
"I've secured for the battalion a week's rest off the line".
我为全营兄弟 争取到一星期的假
That's all.
就这样
Hours like months.
长夜漫漫
Days like years.
度日如年
Walked into the golden age.
我正值青春年华
Stood on the shores of the New World.
站在新世界的边缘
I would've come by and paid you guys a visit,
我本来想去看你们
but...
不过...
I just felt like being alone, you know?
我想一个人静一下
Yeah?
是吗?
We wanted to thank you, sir.
我们要谢谢你
For asking to make that flanking move.
要求进行包抄行动
For watching out for us.
为我们着想
Keeping us together.
让我们团结一致
We're all sorry to see you go.
你不该被调走
We feel like you got a rotten deal.
这不公平
Well, I'm not sure that you're right.
我并不同意
Tough part is...
最难的是
not knowing if you're doing any good.
不知道这么做有没有用
That's the hard part.
这才是最难的
But it doesn't matter. I don't care.
不过无所谓 我不在乎
I'm glad to be going.
我很高兴能离开
I'm glad.
真的很高兴
- There's still time. We could file a complaint. - For what?
- 还是能提出申诉 - 为什么?
What good would that do?
有什么用?
Anyway, I wanna go.
反正我想走
Leave it alone. Let it lay.
别管它 算了吧
(希腊语)
What does that mean, sir?
什么意思?
It means "You've been like my sons".
你们像是我的孩子
You are my sons.
你们是我的孩子
My dear sons.
我亲爱的孩子
You live inside me now.
你们活在我心中
I'll carry you wherever I go.
永远与我同在
Can't nothing make you forget it.
我忘不了战争的可怕
Each time you start from scratch.
悲剧不断重演
War don't ennoble men.
战争不能给我们荣耀
It turns 'em into dogs.
只会把人变成野狗
Poisons the soul.
荼毒我们的心灵
My dear wife,
亲爱的妻子
you get something twisted out of your insides by all this blood, filth, and noise.
战争的丑陋和血腥暴力 会让人丧失良知
I wanna stay changeless for you.
我很想保持纯真
I wanna come back to you the man I was before.
我想以原来的我回到你身边
How do we get to those other shores?
我们该如何获得宁静?
To those blue hills.
回到青山绿水间?
Love.
真爱
Where does it come from?
到底来自何方?
Who lit this flame in us?
谁燃起我们心中的爱火?
No war can put it out,
战争无法熄灭它
conquer it.
或是征服它
I was a prisoner.
我曾是个囚犯
You set me free.
你让我自由
No matter how much training you got,
不管你受过多少训练
how careful you are,
或是多么小心
it's a matter of luck whether or not you get killed.
只要运气不好就会阵亡
Makes no difference who you are, or how tough a guy you might be,
不管你是谁 或是多么骁勇善战
if you're in the wrong spot at the wrong time, you're gonna get it.
一不小心就会被杀死
I look at that boy dying,
我看着那个人死去
I don't feel nothing.
一点感觉都没有
I don't care about nothing any more.
我对一切都不在乎
Sounds like bliss.
听起来很幸福
I don't have that feeling yet.
我还没有那种感觉
That numbness.
麻木不仁的感觉
Not like the rest of you guys.
我跟你们不一样
Maybe cos I knew what to expect.
也许是因为我看得太多
Maybe I was just frozen up already.
根本就失去感觉
I haven't touched another woman since I was called up.
我入伍后就没碰过女人
Or talked to one.
或跟女人说过话
I don't wanna...
我不想...
I don't wanna feel the desire.
我不想有欲念
All right. Abrahams!
亚伯罕
Abrahams. Here you go.
亚伯罕 你的信
Stack! Where's Stack?
史狄 史狄呢?
Bring him out.
叫他来
Bell?
比尔?
Bell!
比尔!
Another one for Bell. Another one for Bell.
另一封是比尔的 另一封是比尔的
Dear Jack,
亲爱的积克
I've met an Air Force captain. I've fallen in love with him.
我认识一个空军上尉 我爱上他
I want a divorce to marry him.
我要跟你离婚嫁给他
I know you can say no, but I'm asking you anyway,
你可以拒绝 但我还是要说
out of the memory of what we had together.
毕竟我们曾夫妻一场
Forgive me.
原谅我
It just got too lonely, Jack.
我太寂寞了
We'll meet again some day.
我们会再见
People who have been as close as we've been always meet again.
我们一定会再见面的
I have no right to speak to you this way.
我无权跟你这么说
I can't stop myself.
不过我忍不住
A habit so strong.
习惯成自然
Oh, my friend of all those shining years.
你曾是我最好的朋友
Help me leave you!
帮助我离开你
What's your name?
你叫什么?
We were a family.
我们曾是一家人
How'd it break up and come apart?
不得已被拆散
So that now we're turned against each other.
现在我们自相残杀
Each standing in the other's light.
断送彼此的生路
How did we lose the good that was given us?
我们怎么会失去善良本性?
Let it slip away?
泯灭天理良知
Scatter it careless?
将人性弃之不顾
What's keeping us from reaching out?
我们为什么无法升华?
Touching the glory?
达到光荣的巅峰?
I'd have had you, Witt, if you was a Jap,Long ago.
如果我是日军你早就死了
They leave you here?
你得留下来?
Yup.
对
I slowed 'em up.
我会拖累他们
Don't mind, really.
我不介意
The medic fixed me up pretty good.
医官帮我包扎得很好
I got plenty of ammo.
我有很多弹药
Somebody'll be along for me eventually.
一定会有人来接我
- They got you good. - Right in the knee.
- 你伤不轻 - 膝盖中弹
Yeah.
是啊
I'm out of this war for good, Witt.
我不必再打仗了 威特
- What you doin' down here? - Just, you know,
- 你在这儿干嘛? - 只是 你知道
I'm heading back to the company.
我要回到连上
Yeah.
好
Well, you give all them boys my best.
跟大伙儿问好
You can come with me if you want.
你可以跟我来
I'll help you along.
我扶你
No, it's nice and quiet.
不了 这里很好
Peaceful up here.
很安静
I'd just slow you up. There'll be somebody along.
我会拖累你 剖队会接我
I'll remind 'em.
我会提醒他们
OK.
好
Hey, Witt.
嘿 威特
Who you making trouble for today?
今天你惹了什么麻烦?
What d'you mean?
什么意思?
Well, isn't that what you like to do?
你不是最爱惹麻烦吗?
Turn left when they say go right?
叫你向左你偏偏向右
Why are you such a troublemaker, Witt?
你为什么这么爱惹麻烦?
You care about me, don't you, Sergeant?
你很关心我 对吧?
I always felt like you did.
我一直都这么觉得
Why do you always make yourself out like a rock?
你为什么装得冷酷无情?
One day I can come up and talk to you,
有时我跟你聊得很愉快
by the next day it's like we never even met.
隔一天 我们就像没见过面似的
Lonely house now.
好孤单的房子
You ever get lonely?
你会觉得孤单吗?
Only around people.
只有在人群中
You still believing in the beautiful light, are you?
你还是有美好的信念 对吧?
How do you do that?
你怎么办得到?
You're a magician to me.
你就像是魔术师
I still see a spark in you.
你眼中仍有一丝良知
One man looks at a dying bird and thinks there's nothing but unanswered pain.
有人看到死去小鸟的眼中 只有无言的痛楚
But death's got the final word.
不过死亡是无情的
It's laughing at him.
死神在嘲笑他
Another man sees that same bird,
有人看着同一只小鸟
feels the glory.
却看到生命光辉
Feels something smiling through him.
心中充满喜悦
We need to get out of here right now.
我们得马上撤退
- You explain to... headquarters the situation? - No.
- 你跟指挥部说过吗? - 没有
Do they know where we are? Cos we're sitting ducks out here.
他们知道我们在这儿吗?
Well, I think that's... up to me to judge, Sergeant.
我们死定了 这要由我决定
I think we just need to send somebody up there and find out how close they are. OK?
我们得派人去看敌军有多近 好吗?
It's easy.
很容易
Hey, Weld... get headquarters on that thing.
韦特 联络指挥部
The fire's coming closer, sir.
炮声越来越近
Line's cut!
没有讯号
We need to send somebody out there to find out where that line is being cut.
我们得派人查出原因
And we need to find out how close they are.
和敌人有多近
Come on.
来吧
OK. OK.
好吧 好吧
Hey, you.
嘿 你
You go.
你去
You're going, Fife.
费夫 你要去
Coombs. You go, too.
古恩 你也去
Come on!
快点
I'll go. I want you to know I think the whole thing's a bad idea, though.
我也去 这整个任务都不对
If they come down here in any strength, Lieutenant, they'll knock our position to hell.
要是他们全力进攻 我们肯定没命
You don't have to go. Others'll volunteer.
你不必去 别人会去
No, I wanna go, sir. In case something bad happens, I wanna be there.
我想要去 万一出事我要在场
All right. You stay by the river.
好吧 顺着河走
That jungle's too thick. And be very careful.
丛林很浓密 小心点
I will.
我会的
Good luck, Witt.
祝好运 威特
You OK, Fife?
费夫 你没事吧?
A reinforce battalion.
敌军的增援部队
We need to go back.
我们得回去
Tell the lieutenant.
告诉连长
Let's go.
走吧
I'm hit!
我中弹了
One of us needs to stay here and hold 'em off.
有人得留下来阻挡敌军
We'll be all right.
我们不会有事的
My friend here doesn't have long,
我的朋友活不久了
so... you go.
你们回去吧
You go on ahead.
快去吧
Witt!
威特
They're coming.
他们来了
I gotta go. I don't want you to be afraid.
我得走了 你不要
Just hide out here till you hear firing, then push on down the river.
听到枪声就躲起来 然后再顺着河走下去
No.
不
- Where's Coombs? - Get back. Get back, they're coming.
- 古恩呢? - 快撤退 敌人来了
Fall back.
撤退
Where's Witt? Fife, where's Witt?
威特呢? 费夫 威特在哪儿?
Fife, where's Witt?
费夫 威特呢?
Fife. Fife, where's Witt?
威特在哪儿?
(日语)
Where's your spark now?
你的生命光辉呢?
Now, I know you men have been making and drinking this goddamn swipe.
我知道你们在喝私酿酒
That's OK by me.
没关系
Everything a lie.
一切都是谎言...
Any man in my outfit can get as drunk as he wants to every night.
在我的部队可以尽管喝酒
Everything you hear and see.
...你见到和听到的一切
As long as he's in shape to make reveille and carry out any assignment given.
只要能执行任务就没问题
If he can't do that, he's gonna have trouble from me.
要是不行...他就会有麻烦
- So much to spew out. - I prefer to think of myself as a family man,
- 他们都在说谎 - 我是个注重家庭的人
and that's what we all are here, whether we like it or not.
大家才会在一起
We are a family.
我们是一家人
I'm the father.
我是父亲
Guess that makes Sergeant Welsh here the mother.
副连长就是母亲
They just keep coming, one after another.
他们一个接一个来
That makes you all the children in this family.
你们都是我的孩子
Now, a family can have only one head, and that is the father.
一家之主是父亲
Father's the head, mother runs it. That's the way it's gonna work here.
男主外女主内 这就是规矩
- If any of you wanna see me about anything, - You're in a box.
- 要是你们想见我 - 我们被困在棺材里
- anything at all, - A moving box.
- 只要有任何事 - 移动的棺材
you will find that I am available.
我都会在
This war is not gonna be over by next Christmas.
战争在圣诞节前不会结束
It's gonna be a long time before we get home...
还要很久才能回家
They want you dead.
他们要我们牺牲
Or in their lie.
或相信他们的谎言
Only one thing a man can do.
我们只有一个办法
Find something that's his.
找到自己的出路
Make an island for himself.
逃到属于自己的小岛
If I never meet you in this life,
我这一生若不相信上帝
Let me feel the lack.
将会有所缺憾
A glance from your eyes, and my life will be yours.
上帝怜悯我 我就属于他
Somethin' I can come back to. Some kind of foundation.
我只期望有一天能回家
I mean, I don't know what, you know, what your plans are, but...
我不知道你有何打算 但...
I'm determined now. I've been through the thick and thin of it.
吃了这么多苦 我已经觉悟
You know, I may be young, but I've lived plenty of life.
我还年轻 不过经历苦难
I'm ready to start living it good.
我准备好好活下去
You know, my daddy always told me it's gonna get a lot worse before it gets better.
我爸常说 苦尽甘来
You know, cos life ain't supposed to be that hard when you're young.
年轻人的日子不应该那么苦
Well, I figure after this the worst is gonna be gone.
我猜最苦的已经熬过去了
It's time for things to get better. That's what I want.
往后会渐入佳境 这是我的愿望
That's what's gonna happen.
一定能够实现
I'm getting older now.
我长大了
By no means old, but older.
我变得比较成熟
Where is it that we were together?
我们曾经在哪里一起渡过
Who were you that I lived with?
你们曾跟我一起生活
Walked with?
你们是什么人?
The brother.
是兄弟
The friend.
也是朋友
Darkness from light.
黑暗和光明
Strife from love.
仇恨和爱
Are they the workings of one mind?
全都来自同一个心灵
The features of the same face?
拥有同一张脸孔吗?
Oh, my soul,
我的灵魂
Let me be in you now.
让我相信上帝
Look out through my eyes.
透过我的双眼观看世界
Look out at the things you made.
看着您创造的万物
All things shining.
散发生命光辉